David Ramos

Full Stack Software Developer



+504 3298 3065

davidramos015@gmail.com

- % davidramos-om.com
- San Pedro Sula, Honduras

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Experienced software developer with over 10 years in .Net and JavaScript roadmaps and a strong background in business development across various industries. Working proficiently in English and native Spanish speaker with excellent communication skills. Proven ability to work autonomously and remotely in goal-oriented environments, continuously learning and striving to improve my skill set.

EXPERTISE

INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Self-motivation

Teamwork and collaboration

Ownership mentality

Always making something

Comfy in startups environments

Relentless problem solver

UI & UX Passionate

Autonomy to work remotely

HARD SKILLS

JavaScript	Proficient
HTML & CSS	Competent
Node JS & Nest JS	Competent
#C & .Net Stack	Proficient
MS SQL Server	Proficient
PostgreSQL	Competent
WinForms & DevExpress	Proficient
WordPress	Advance newb
React & Next JS	Proficient
Graph QL & Rest APIs	Proficient
Web3 Libraries	Advance newb
Ethereum Blockchain	Advance newb
Material UI	Proficient
Chakra UI	Proficient
Git & Version Control	Proficient

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Software Developer

2020 - Present

Developp L.L.C. • Texas, United States of America

- Implement the latest tech stack versions to promote better lifecycle practices, speed up development by 30%, and reduce technical debt.
- Building GraphQL APIs with Nest JS and PostgreSQL.
- Take ownership of the e-commerce platform and enhance its design and development.

Aguas de San Pedro • Honduras

2013 - 2020

Software Architect

Dec 2019 - Sept 2020

- Orchestrated numerous internal & third-party software implementations.
- Coded core program and APIS development, server setups, and flowchart to document the processes

Project Manager

April 2018 - Dec 2019

- Worked directly with end-users to maximize efficiencies and user-friendliness.
- Led the upgrade on end-user services such as the corp. website, mobile apps, and digital kiosks in branches.
- Employed strong skills to help to recruit at tech test steps and onboard new talent.
- Closely worked with staff under my charge, business analysts, and developers to successfully implement an enterprise-wide system.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

August 2013 – April 2018

Aguas de San Pedro • Honduras

Senior and Lead Developer

- Carried out software maintenance by making modifications as required.
- Delivered products built on C# using DevExpress UI for windows form and Vue and ReactJS web apps
- Built mobile apps for multi-devices like handhelds and android O.S
- Collaborated with teams to code apps such as in-site invoicing, quality ISO management, budget, warehouse, logistics, accounting, vehicle control, work orders, and vendor modules.

May 2011 - August 2013 Grupo Leitz • Honduras

Senior Software Developer

- Since Leitz is a nearshoring and tailored solutions company, I was assigned to four corporations while at my firm (Chiquita Brands, British American Tobacco Honduras, ASP, and Affinity Consulting).
- Teamwork in Rolling Forecast, MicroStrategy (BI), Chiquita Reporting Services, and Scheduling & Notification services.
- Collaborate on all the stages of the systems development life cycle.

March 2009 - May 2011 Cia. Software IQ S. de R. L. • Honduras

Junior Developer

- Addressed and fixed complex issues.
- Teamwork at building a Human Resources, Payroll, and Accounting System using VB.Net 2008, C#.NET 2008, SQL Server 2008 and DevExpress
- Acquired experience through the implementation of the software for five clients.

EDUCATION

2022

English Academic Year Level (B2+ CEFR) Atlas Language School, Dublin D02 YH79, Ireland

2018

Scrum Master Accredited Certification Issued by International Scrum Institute TM #65125423023477

2014 - 2017

Degree in Computer Science

Centro Universitario Tecnológico (CEUTEC) San Pedro Sula, Corte, Honduras

2009 - 2013

Computer Systems Engineering

Universidad Tecnológica Centroamericana (UNITEC)

San Pedro Sula, Corte, Hondura.